Charybdis, the calamity, has awakened,
（リムル）
厄災 カリュブディスが目覚めた
and it's heading straight
toward the capital city of Rimuru.
まっすぐに
中央都市リムルに向かってくる
It seems like I'm the one
it's after... I think.
目的は 俺… みたい
多分
The forces we have ready
to go up against Charybdis
（リムル）
カリュブディスに対する
こちらの戦力は
are Benimaru's group,
Gobta and the Goblin riders,
ベニマルたちに
ゴブタらゴブリンライダー
the High Orcs led by Geld,
ゲルド率いるハイオークたち
Gabiru and his men,
ガビルと その部下
and some help sent by King Gazel:
そして ガゼル王からの助太刀—
100 Pegasus Knights,
led by the knight captain Dorf.
騎士団長ドルフ率いる
ペガサスナイツ100騎
Their presence here is definitely reassuring.
非常に心強い存在だ
（ガゼル）フンッ
It's only natural that I help
my junior in his time of need.
（ガゼル）
弟弟子(でし)が困っているのなら
助けるのは当然だろう
Yes, sir.
For some reason, King Gazel likes
to think of himself as my senior...
（リムル）
なんか 兄弟子風(でしかぜ)を
吹かせたがるんだよなあ
ガゼル王
Well, ready to do this?
（リムル）さて やるか！
Yes, sir!
That Time I Got Reincarnated as a Slime
Episode 19: Charybdis
（ベニマル）くらえ ヘルフレア！
Eat this! Hell Flare!
That's my Benimaru.
He toasted that thing to a crisp.
（リムル）
さすがベニマル
こんがりと よく焼けた
But...
しかし…
It's shocking that even his attack
wasn't enough to destroy it.
（シュナ）
お兄様の攻撃でも消滅しないとは
驚きです
Is that one of Charybdis's skills?
（リムル）
カリュブディスのスキルか？
Notice.
Notice
（大賢者(だいけんじゃ)）
告…
エクストラスキル“魔力妨害”で
With the extra skill Magic Jamming,
Magic
Jamming
the movement of magicules in a
300-meter radius is disturbed,
半径300メートルの範囲内は
魔素(まそ)の動きが乱され
reducing the efficacy of magic.
魔法の効果が低下します
So this guy's going to be trouble...
（リムル）面倒な相手だ…
Stick to the plan! Scatter them
and strike each one individually!
予定どおり分散させて
各個撃破だ！
（ゲルド）
くっ… 俺が動きを止める
I'll stop it from moving! All of you, attack!
お前たちが攻撃しろ！
Sir Geld!
（オーク）ゲルド様！
Attack!
やれえ〜！
Well, now what?
（ゲルド）
さて どうする？
My comrades can't do anything
now, so to attack this thing...
仲間は動けない
こいつを攻撃する手段は…
Let me give you a hand!
（ガビル）助太刀いたしますぞ〜！
Vortex Crash!
ボルテクスクラ〜ッシュ！
Sir Gabiru, you're so cool!
（部下Ａ）ガビル様 かっこい〜！
（部下Ｂ）しかり
Indeed!
Tend to the wounded!
（ガビル）ケガ人の手当てを！
We're on it!
（部下Ｃ）任せとけ！
Since you stopped it, I had a
much easier time taking it down!
（ガビル）
ゲルド殿が
動きを止めてくださったおかげで
楽にしとめることができましたぞ！
Thank you for the assistance, Gabiru.
助太刀 感謝する　ガビル殿
We'll bring that one down!
You can take it from there!
我が輩たちが落とす
あとはゲルド殿！
Right! I'll stop it myself this time!
うむ 今度は しとめてみせる
Sir Gabiru, you're so cool!
ガビル様 かっくい〜！
我がペガサスナイツの
誇りにかけて
On the pride of the Pegasus Knights,
we will stop them here and now!
ここで阻止するのだ！
（ゴブタ）
うう… 一旦 退却っす〜！
Fall back for now!
（ゴブタ）でやあ〜！
（ハクロウ）ホッホ〜
Some will divert, others will attack.
おとり役と攻撃役
きちんと自らの役割を見極めよ
Enter this battle with a clear
understanding of your own role...
and without fear of death!
死ぬ気でなあ
（リムル）
ハクロウの采配 見事なもんだ
Hakurou's such a pro at giving orders.
Regaining his youth has allowed him
to refine his tough teaching style.
若返って鬼教官ぶりに
磨きがかかったからなあ
（ミリム）
なあ 私も一緒に遊びたい
Hey, I wanna play, too!
Why are you here?
Didn't I tell you to wait back in town?
なんで ここにいるの？
町で待ってろって言ったよね？
B-But I can watch, at least, can't I?
け… 見学ぐらい いいであろう？
町にいても暇なのだ
Staying in town is boring!
Come on, I'll just—
なあなあ やはり 私が…
No!
（リムル）ダメ
（ミリム）うっ…
Looking at me like that won't help.
（リムル）そんな目で見てもダメだ
（ソーカ）ソウエイ様 今です
Now, Master Souei!
Right!
（ソウエイ）うむ
Puppet Strings!
Wow! He's manipulating the Megalodons
to make them fight each other!
メガロドンを操って
同士討ちにさせているのだ
もう何でもありだな あのイケメン
Anything goes for that dreamboat, huh?
頃合いを見て始末しろ
Wait for the right moment, then kill it.
心得ました
あとは お任せください
Understood. Leave the rest to us.
They're flying? When did Ranga learn that?
空を？
ランガのヤツ どこで あんな技を…
Also, when did he team up with Shion?
というか いつ シオンとコンビに？
（シオン）
今回は なんとしても活躍し
目立たねばなりません
I must play an active role
and stand out this time.
Indeed. I feel the same way!
（ランガ）
うむ 我も その意見には賛成だ！
断頭鬼刃(だんとうきじん)！
Decapitating Demon Blade!
Decapitating Demon Blade
私も 私も〜！
Let me, too! Let me, too!
I told you, it's not happening.
（リムル）ダメだって言ってるだろ
むう…
フウ…
さて 残るは…
Now, that just leaves...
Let's see just how strong it is!
（ランガ）
どの程度の強さなのか
見極めてやろうではないか
That's our Ranga!
それでこそランガ
Disappointing.
（ハクロウ）ふがいないのう
それなりに成長しておるが
たった１匹も しとめられぬとは
You have improved a bit, but to think
you couldn't even stop one of them...
You will need much tougher training.
修行を
ますます厳しくせねばならんわい
ちょっ… これ以上 厳しくされると
死んじゃうっすよ じじい！
Hey! Anything tougher than this
is gonna kill me, old man!
Old man, you say?
“じじい”じゃと？
リムル様
Great Rimuru.
あとは カリュブディスだけか
So all that's left now is Charybdis...
あいつの実力なら大丈夫でしょう
With his ability, it shouldn't be a problem.
Besides...
それに…
しっかし デケえなあ
That thing sure is huge, though...
Answer.
Answer
（大賢者）
解　規模から推測して
Judging from its size, the—
（大賢者）高度…
（リムル）いや いいから
I don't need to hear it!
If you're gonna say something,
tell me the easiest way to beat it.
（リムル）
どうせなら
簡単に倒す方法を教えてくれよ
Now she shuts up...
黙りやがった
全然 効いてないみたいだな
Looks like they're not even leaving a mark.
（ベニマル）ですね
True.
It might try to pull something!
Don't let your guard down!
（念話:リムル）
何か仕掛けてくるかもしれない
油断するなよ！
（シオン）了解です
（ソウエイ）承知
Roger!
Right!
Understood, Master!
（ランガ）
心得ました 我が主(あるじ)よ！
Evade! Get away from it!
回避！　距離を取れ！
ぐっ… よけられん
I can't dodge them!
よける？　何を甘えたことを！
Dodge? Don't be a weakling!
うっ… ぐは！
Souei, use Shadow Movement to escape.
（ランガ）ソウエイよ
ぬしは“影移動”で逃げるがいい
I will act as Shion's shield.
我がシオンの盾となろう！
バカな 死ぬ気か ランガ？
You fool! Do you want to die, Ranga?!
I'll do this alone!
ここは 私一人で
Great Rimuru's chosen course of action is the
one granting the highest chance of survival.
リムル様ならば 生き残る確率が
高いほうを選択されるだろう
Highest chance of survival, eh?
生き残る確率か…
ならば 俺も残ろう
In that case, I'll stay, too.
Oh, don't get the wrong idea.
ああ 勘違いするなよ
The real me will withdraw before
I get killed, so don't worry.
死ぬ前に“本体”は撤退するから
気にするな
フフ…
ソウエイらしいな
Typical Souei...
In that case, let us all survive!
それでは
全員で生き残りましょう
You guys really are idiots.
（リムル）
ホント お前らってバカだよな
こういうときくらい
俺を頼ってくれよ
You could at least rely
on me at a time like this.
Great Rimuru!
（シオン）リムル様！
Devour all! Gluttony!
（リムル）
食らい尽くせ グラトニー！
All those scales, in a mere instant...
（ソウエイ）
あれだけの鱗(うろこ)が 一瞬で…
Leave the rest to me.
You guys fall back and rest for a bit.
あとは俺に任せろ
お前たちは 一旦下がって
少し休むといい
我々は まだ お役に！
We can still help you!
Take it easy. Look.
慌てるなって　あれを見ろ
鱗が再生を始めている
The scales are starting to regenerate.
The next time it uses those,
次に あれを使われたとき
I don't know if I'll be
able to protect you again.
また守ってやれるか
分からないからな
I'll fight it for a while.
Attack at Benimaru's order.
しばらく俺が相手をするから
ベニマルの指示で攻撃するんだ
ご武運を
I wish you luck.
お気をつけて リムル様
Be careful, Great Rimuru!
Master, I will return to help you shortly!
（ランガ）
我が主よ すぐに応援に戻ります！
Yeah.
さてと…
やるだけやってみるとしますか
Now, then... I guess I'll
just do whatever I can.
うっ… わっと
あ〜あ…
おっと
う〜ん 少しは痛がってる… か？
Is it actually hurting... a little?
But...
でも…
Hey, does this thing have Rapid Regeneration?
なあ こいつ“超速再生”を
持ってるんじゃないか？
Answer
Answer.
（大賢者）
解　体組織の修復速度から判断し
Judging from the speed at which
it repairs its body tissue,
there is no doubt that
the individual Charybdis
個体名カリュブディスが
エクストラスキル“超速再生”を
possesses the extra skill
"Ultraspeed Regeneration."
Extra Skill
Ultraspeed
Regeneration
所持していると考えて
間違いありません
Using Ultraspeed Regeneration,
it is estimated that
（大賢者）
鱗の再生は“超速再生”で
３分程度で完了すると推測
it will regenerate all its
scales within three minutes.
So we have three minutes before a
repeat of what it did earlier...
３分で また さっきのあれが
放たれるようになると…
ハア…
Everyone, utilize all methods at
your disposal to attack Charybdis!
全員 持てる手段を尽くして
カリュブディスを攻撃しろ！
効きが悪くてもいい
ヤツに回復の暇を与えるな！
Even if the effects are weak!
Don't give it a chance to recover!
Yeah!
The support of the Pegasus Knights
increased our strength more than tenfold,
（リムル）
ペガサスナイツの援軍も加え
戦力は十分以上
so we thought we'd take down
with an all-out attack, but...
総攻撃で 一気に撃墜…
と思ったのだが
（リムル）フウ…
I think Charybdis is damaged
by about 30% at most...
カリュブディスのダメージは
せいぜい３割ってとこか
An all-out attack managed 30%...
This is looking bad.
総力戦で３割… これはマズいな
What do we do?
（リムル）
どうしたものか…
（カリュブディス）グ… グギュ…
D-Damn you...
（カリュブディス）おのれ… ミ…
M-Milim...
ミリ… ミリムめ
ミリム？
Milim?
You just said "Milim," didn't you?
ミリムって言ったよな？
Great Sage, use Appraisal!
大賢者 “解析鑑定”を！
Answer
Answer.
（大賢者）
解　カリュブディスの依代(よりしろ)となった
Signs of life confirmed from the
body that Charybdis has occupied.
素体の生命反応を確認
The body appears to possess intense anger.
その素材が 強烈な怒りの感情を
持っているもよう
Anger
Intense anger?
強烈な怒り？
Toward Milim?
ミリムに？
So basically, Charybdis headed toward
our town because Milim was there?
つまり カリュブディスは
ミリムがいたから
俺たちの町に向かって来た
ってことか？
I thought it had figured out
that Veldora was inside me...
てっきり俺の中にヴェルドラが
いるのを察知して… とか
深読みし過ぎていたのか
I guess I was overthinking it.
あれ？
Wait!
じゃあ
ミリムに頼っていいんじゃね？
Can't I depend on Milim for this, then?!
Hey, she's asleep!
って 寝てるし！
Milim!
（念話:リムル）ミリム！
（ミリム）ひっ！
ぐわわ！
I wasn't asleep! I was awake the whole time!
寝てないのだ
起きていたのだ！
No, you were obviously asleep.
いや どう見ても寝てたし
I was just meditating!
瞑想(めいそう)していただけだ
I was really cheering you guys on!
ちゃんと
お前たちを応援していたのだぞ
ハア…
Listen, this guy seems to
have business with you.
あのな こいつ どうやら
お前に用事があるみたいなんだけど
What?!
なに！
むむっ あいつは
この前来た フォビオとやらを
It looks like it's using that guy who came
into town, Phobio, as its physical body.
依代にしているようだな
That guy? Really?
あいつか…
Anyway, I had you sit this one out because
I thought he was after me, but...
でな 俺への客かと
思ってたから
お前に遠慮して
もらってたんだが…
もしかして
私が相手してもいいのか？
Are you gonna say I can fight him?!
ギューン！
ハッハ〜！
He was here for you, and we were
just in the way. Sorry about that.
お前のお客だったのに
俺たちが邪魔したみたいで悪いな
いいのだ 気にするな！　なのだ
It's fine! Don't worry about it!
I'll get him!
（ミリム）やるのだ！
（リムル）あっ それと…
Oh, also...
Phobio works for the
Demon Lord Carrion, right?
（リムル）
フォビオって
魔王カリオンの配下なんだろ？
So I'd like to let him
live and help him out...
生かして助けてやりたいんだが…
ワ〜ハッハッハ！
その程度 造作もない
That won't be a problem!
I'll show you how much restraint
I've learned recently!
最近学んだ手加減を見せてやるのだ
（リムル）
うっ 手加減…
Restraint?
Does she really mean that?
ホントだろうな？
Get away from here immediately!
（ドルフ）
速やかに この場から離れろ！
（カリュブディス）
グ… グギョ〜！
Mili... Milim!
ミリ… ミリム〜！
I've already seen that trick.
その技は もう見たのだ
Now, I'll show you one of mine.
今度は私が見せてやろう
これが…
This is...
what you call "restraint"!
手加減というものだ〜！
Drago Buster!
ドラゴバスター！
Where the hell is the "restraint"?
（リムル）手加減って 一体…
あれだ！
There he is!
Gotcha.
よっと…
That was some nice restraint.
見事な手加減だったよ
（ミリム）ヘッヘヘ〜
Notice.
（大賢者）
告　個体名フォビオから
The magicore of Charybdis has been
removed from Phobio and consumed.
個体名カリュブディスの魔核(まかく)を分離
捕食しました
Preparing to isolate it and begin Appraisal.
隔離して“解析鑑定”を行います
Appraisal
フウ…
That should do it.
（リムル）これでよしと…
Rimuru.
（ドルフ）リムル殿
Oh, Dorf-san. I appreciate your help.
（リムル）
ドルフさん　助力を感謝する
We were able to defeat
Charybdis thanks to you.
おかげで
カリュブディスを倒すことができた
No, it wasn't us who defeated Charybdis.
いえ カリュブディスを倒したのは
我々ではなく…
Could you explain what this is all about?
（ドルフ）
説明してもらえますでしょうか？
Well, um, actually...
（リムル）いや その… 実は
this girl is called
Demon Lord Milim, and... you see?
この少女は
魔王ミリムといって… ね？
Demon Lord?
魔王…
（ミリム）フフン
ハハハハ！
リムル殿は冗談がお好きなようだ
I see you have a fondness for jokes, Rimuru!
（ドルフ）
あのような高出力の魔法兵器を
所持していたのなら
If you had such a powerful magical weapon,
I wish you had said so from the start!
最初に
そう申してほしかったですぞ
It's no joke! I'm a Demon Lord!
冗談ではない！
私は魔王なのだ
I defeated Charybdis!
私が
カリュブディスを殺(や)ったのだ！
I see. You wish to keep the
specifics of your weapon secret.
なるほど 兵器については秘密と…
I understand that.
分かりますぞ
奥の手は
隠しておくに限りますからな
It's always best to keep
your trump card hidden.
魔王だと言っておるだろう！
I'm telling you, I'm a Demon Lord!
Charybdis could have had catastrophic
effects on all mankind,
（ドルフ）
人類にとっても災禍と成りうる
カリュブディスを始末できたのは
so its defeat is most fortuitous.
僥倖(ぎょうこう)でした
I must report to my king,
so I will take my leave now.
私も王への報告がありますれば
今回は これにて失礼いたします
Hey, damn it!
（ミリム）おい こら〜！
本当に助かりました
You were a great help.
ガゼル王に
よろしくお伝えください
Give King Gazel my regards.
Hey. You awake?
（リムル）よっ 目覚めたか？
ここは… どこだ？
Where... am I?
What... What did I...
俺は… 俺は 一体…
Do you remember what you did?
（リムル）
自分が何をしたか覚えているか？
I'm so sorry!
すみませんでした！
I've done something
unthinkable to Lady Milim,
俺は ミリム様に
とんでもないことを…
and I've caused so much trouble for you!
あなた方にも
迷惑をかけてしまったようで
（リムル）なんで こんなことを…
Why did you do—
（トレイニー）
なぜ カリュブディスの封印場所を
知っていたのですか？
How did you know where Charybdis was sealed?
We won't accept that you
just happened to find it.
（トライア）
偶然 見つけた… などとは
言わせませんよ
You heard her.
（リムル）…だそうだ
Right... You see...
（フォビオ）あっ はい それは…
（トレイニー）
ティアと… フットマンと名乗る
仮面の道化
Masked harlequins named Tear and Footman?
Did the mask look like this?
こんな仮面でしたか？
No, the ones I met were a girl in
a mask with a tear under one eye
（フォビオ）
いや… 俺の前に現れたのは
涙目の仮面の少女と
and a heavy man with an angry mask.
怒った仮面の太った男だった
Um...
（ガビル）
あの〜 その ラプラス殿も…
That Laplace guy also..
（リムル）ラプラス？
Laplace?
ラプラス殿は
ゲルミュッドの使いとして
Laplace once showed up before
me as a servant of Gelmud.
我が輩の前に現れた者なのですが
He was wearing a mask like
the one Treyni described.
今 トレイニー殿が
おっしゃった仮面を
かぶっておりましたぞ
Also, he called himself the vice
president of a jack-of-all-trades group
（ガビル）
それに 中庸道化連(ちゅうようどうけれん)という
何でも屋の副会長だと
名乗っておりましたな
called the Moderate Harlequin Alliance.
Well, now the dots are connected.
（リムル）点と点が つながったな
I see.
（トレイニー）なるほど
And this person's name was Laplace?
あの者の名は
ラプラスというのですね
Footman, huh?
フットマンね…
We'll have to remember that name.
その名 覚えておくとしよう
Yes, Brother.
ええ お兄様
A mysterious jack-of-all-trades group,
the Moderate Harlequin Alliance?
（リムル）
謎の何でも屋 中庸道化連か…
They pretend they're helping you,
協力するふうを装い
then use you to fulfill their goals
without getting their own hands dirty...
自分の手を汚さずに
相手を利用して目的を果たす
They sound like they'll be trouble.
やっかいそうな相手だな
（ミリム）
むむ？　私は何も知らないのだ
I don't know anything about them!
むしろ
そんな面白そうなヤツらがいるなら
In fact, if fun people like that are
really out there, I wanna meet them!
ぜひとも会ってみたかったのだ
（リムル）ふむ…
It may be that it wasn't Gelmud,
もしかすると
ゲルミュッドではなく
but Clayman who's plotting
something in secret.
クレイマンのヤツが 何か
たくらんでいたのかもしれないな
内緒(ないしょ)で
Clayman?
（リムル）クレイマン？
（ミリム）
ん？　ヤツは
そういうたくらみが大好きなのだ
He loves coming up with schemes like that.
The Demon Lord Clayman...
（リムル）魔王クレイマンか…
Regardless of whose scheme I was roped into,
（フォビオ）
誰のたくらみに乗せられたといえど
what happened was my own responsibility.
今回の一件は俺の責任だ
It has nothing to do with Demon
Lord Carrion, so please...
魔王カリオン様は関係ない
だから
俺の命ひとつで許してほしい
Take my life and leave him out of this!
Next time, be more on your toes
so you won't be fooled again.
（リムル）
次からは もっと用心して
だまされないようにしろよ
Huh?
You can move now, right? So you can go.
（リムル）
もう動けるだろ？　行っていいぞ
But... what I did was unforgivable!
いや… 俺は許されないだろ
I don't even want your life.
（リムル）
別に お前の命はいらないって
Right, Milim?
なあ ミリム？
Yeah, totally!
うむ 当然なのだ
I thought I'd give him just one little whack,
軽く１発くらい殴ってやろうかと
思っていたが
but I've matured so much, after all.
私も大人になったものだな
You were going to hit him?
（リムル）
殴るつもりだったのかよ
全然 腹が立っていないから
許してやるぞ！
I'm not mad at all, so I forgive you!
There you go. So don't worry about it.
（リムル）
ということだ　気にするなよ
That's right!
そうだぞ
カリオンも それでいいだろ？
That's okay with you, right, Carrion?
L-Lord Carrion!
カ… カリオン様！
（カリオン）
フンッ 気付いていたのか ミリム
So you figured it out, Milim?
Of course I did!
（ミリム）当然なのだ
So this guy is the Demon Lord Carrion...
（リムル）
そうか こいつが魔王カリオン
Yo.
（カリオン）よう
Thanks for sparing this guy's life.
そいつを殺さずに助けてくれたこと
礼を言うぜ
You're the masked majin who
defeated Gelmud, are you not?
（カリオン）
お前が ゲルミュッドを殺った
仮面の魔人なんだろ？
Yeah, that's right.
（リムル）ああ そのとおりだ
仕返しにでも来たのか？
Are you here to avenge him?
フッ いや…
Nah. Get up.
（カリオン）立て
（フォビオ）は… はい！
Y-Yes, sir!
（カリオン）悪かったな
（リムル）え？
Sorry about that.
Huh?
It seems my underling
here was out of control.
（カリオン）
部下が暴走しちまったようだ
That means I was negligent in his oversight.
俺の監督不行き届きってことで
許してやってほしい
I hope you'll forgive him.
S-Sure...
今回の件 借りにしておく
I owe you one after all this.
何かあれば
俺様を頼ってくれていい
If anything comes up,
you can always count on me.
In that case, I'd appreciate it if you'd
enter a non-aggression pact with our nation.
（リムル）
それなら
俺たちの国との不可侵協定を
結んでくれるとうれしいんだが
That's all you want? Very well.
（カリオン）
そんなことでいいのか？
よかろう
The Demon Lord... no...
魔王の… いや
The Beastmaster of the Animal
Kingdom of Eurazania, Carrion,
獣王国(じゅうおうこく)ユーラザニア
“獅子王(ビーストマスター)”カリオンの名にかけて
swears on his name to never
raise a blade to your nation.
貴様たちに刃(やいば)を向けぬと誓ってやる
Thanks.
よし
All right.
Come on, we're out.
ほら 帰んぞ
Uh, he's losing tons of blood!
いっぱい血 出てますけど！
では また会おう リムル
Well, I'll see you again, Rimuru.
Now, then...
さてと…
終わったな
I guess that's over.
俺たちも帰ろう！
Let's head home.
Yes, sir!
（一同）はい！
Next time, "Yuuki Kagurazaka."
（大賢者）
次回「ユウキ･カグラザカ」
Yuuki Kagurazaka